<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.1.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-10-30T19:45:30+01:00</updated><id>/</id><title>Hey Mulder blog</title><subtitle>The &#39;90s are back.</subtitle><entry><title>the Radio</title><link href="/the-radio/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="the Radio" /><published>2016-10-30T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-10-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/the-radio</id><content type="html" xml:base="/the-radio/">&lt;p&gt;Dancing and singing to “Rhythm is a Dancer” by SNAP! shaped my childhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wore that shit out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When that song came on, I left my small town and teleported into another universe dancing my troubles away. The radio station, 102.5 The Party, was my dancing fuel. I even had a choreographed dance routine to Rhythm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Radio in the ’90s was a big a deal for me. Switching from The Party to 96 KIX kept me fresh to the latest jams. Casey Kasem’s Weekly Top 40 was also among the stops I’d find myself each week. The Party focused on dance and pop hits and KIX was your destination for R&amp;amp;B/hip-hop. KIX introduced me to En Vogue, Tag Team, Blackstreet, Montell Jordan and Tupac. It even taught me how to do the Tootsee Roll dance because the butterfly was old. If I wanted Guns N’ Roses or U2, I went to Rock 92.3. Through the week, I fueled on KIX, but Friday nights were about The Party and I never missed Casey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, living in Seattle made my ’90s radio dreams come true with HOT 103.7 because they only play ’90s and ’00s hits. They’ve led me to revist my love of radio and make me feel right at home. I listen to the radio when I wake up, when I shower, when I go to work, while I’m eating and when I get home in the evening. My radio even comes with me when I travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fun Facts: I met Wolfman Jack when I was a kid and totally geeked out. Also, if you don’t know about my love for Montell Jordan’s “This Is How We Do It,” ask me about it sometime.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary>Dancing and singing to “Rhythm is a Dancer” by SNAP! shaped my childhood.</summary></entry><entry><title>You’re up and running!</title><link href="/Hello-World/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="You&#39;re up and running!" /><published>2014-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/Hello-World</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Hello-World/">&lt;p&gt;Next you can update your site name, avatar and other options using the _config.yml file in the root of your repository (shown below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/config.png&quot; alt=&quot;_config.yml&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to make your first post is to edit this one. Go into /_posts/ and update the Hello World markdown file. For more instructions head over to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/barryclark/jekyll-now&quot;&gt;Jekyll Now repository&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary>Next you can update your site name, avatar and other options using the _config.yml file in the root of your repository (shown below).</summary></entry></feed>
